Shishio Tournament
I felt like looking back on how I was defeated last time
Anyway, let's continue
Look man here black moves bishop six one white moves pawn five two
Then black can move his pawn here to seven four you're wrong
Why should black needlessly move the bishop when his pawn can just as easily go to seven four
Are you the type that gets yourself killed by moving your pieces around too much?
Huh what could you be talking about you seem like the type of guy that acts like he's brave
But really is constantly checking his surroundings and you still manage to get surrounded without realizing it
Like a bunny about to be eaten by wolves
You don't want my pawn to take your bishop do you but I can take it if I want and there's nothing you can do
Taking the bishop first is such a cheap move
Black moving pawn to seven four is obviously the best move
If black moves gold to six four and pawn to seven four moving bishop to six one won't make sense
It'll be a better route to take my pawn and go to three five and take your bishop at seven one
Meow
So you'll just leave my pawn five two unattended while your rook five eights wide open that sounds like a great idea
All right, then how about my bishop six one takes your gold six four
How could you even hope to get close to my gold when you can't even take my pawn seven four?
You let me take your pawn five two then I won
But what if bishop four seven takes my pawn seven four then what in that case wouldn't I just go pawn to five six?
What's wrong having a hard time keeping up with my flawless logic?
You need to go back to first then
I
Finally quieted down
I can't believe that still works once you've solved it. Please take your seat
So I'd like to know what you think kiriyama
What would you take the bishop at six one or just have the pawn go straight for seven four?
Either way
It's kind of too late
By the time the board had gotten to this position. I think you were already in trouble
Stop undermining what we're doing here that defeats the whole purpose of our workshop
Yeah, but unless we treat it like we would a real game. There's no point in studying it
So in other words, what I mean is something needed to be done before the board got to this point
Then explain exactly how looking at the board as it is provides no help
Isn't it clear to see I mean let me think about it. How can I put this?
It just feels like it's unsettling. Huh? It seems unsettling?
Unsettling huh? What's that supposed to mean? Sounds like you're just making it up
Did you think saying something abstract would make you sound smart? Is that it?
Be more specific. What do you mean? Tell us now or do you want me to make you talk?
Hey, what do you think you're doing with my cactus?
Sorry kiriyama
This is a workshop so try to explain yourself
I know you're used to studying alone and don't usually have to voice your opinion
But try your best now go ahead
Well, let's see
First of all
Silver three seven is still on the board
It just really stands out to me and a sort of unsettling
Okay, tell me what else
Well, let me think about it
It seems like pawn to seven four is a bad move
All it does is set you up for more damage
More damage? Come on, it's not that simple
Yeah, I'm surprised to say it but I'm starting to agree with the steamed bun
Steamed bun?
Wanna go outside?
Right now
If you want to step outside that'd make my day
That's too loud
Please try to keep it down
Or I'll have to kill you
I see
Unsettling
Huh
Interesting
Well, see you next time
Yeah, I'll check my schedule and let you know when I'm free again
Okay, great
Uh, kiriyama
Yeah
I was wondering if you might be free tomorrow afternoon
Think so
I shouldn't have anything planned for later in the day tomorrow
Are you free tomorrow afternoon?
It'll just be us this time
That's what Mr. Shimada said
So on the next day
Hey, come on in
Thanks for coming back today
Wow, have you gotten any sleep?
Yeah, I slept
More like I passed out
Sitting at the board
Can I get you something to drink?
That's okay
I'll get it
What would you like?
Oh
I'll have some hot coffee, please
But I only have instant
There, here you go
Thanks
One more loss and the next one is do or die
All straight losses
I can't let that happen
Whether I get to play in my hometown or not is the least of my worries
I just need two wins
The sixth match is going to be held in my hometown
Oh yeah, so where is your hometown?
Oh, it's in Yamagata
Yamagata
Uh, so what's it like out there?
Oh, just a whole lot of snow
What about when there isn't any snow?
There are mountains and rivers and some rice paddies
Yeah
And that's about all there is
Well, at least they have some rice paddies
Yeah
But they've been reducing the acreage
There aren't a whole lot of rice paddies left
But listen to me
You're not getting a very good picture of the place, are you?
The truth is
It's a place that would be happiest left alone
And that goes for people
Schools and homes
And even more rice paddies
And that's...
That's the reason
I didn't hear what he said
But I have a feeling
He said exactly why
Well, guess we should get started
Can you begin with the castle opening?
You remember the board from yesterday, right?
Just like that
Here I go
King to 8-8
Pawn to 9-5
Rook to 3-8
What is this?
Knight to 7-3
Pawn to 1-6
Bishop to 4-2
Silver to 3-7
Silver to 5-3
They're rushing at me
Shimada's thoughts are like
A raging river pulling me under
Team 2-5
It's a powerful weapon
Five, four
Oh, crap. I was sleeping.
I could have died just now.
I see.
I came home.
Oh, man. My shoulder. My eyes.
What is this?
I feel exhausted.
When I thought about it, that was the first time I can ever remember being subjected to an A-class player's thoughts.
It was like being in a muddy stream.
But I wouldn't retreat or let myself be swept away, so I held on. Desperately.
I'm...
No. Both of us are pros.
It's not a one-sided relationship. It's something that, in the end, we both hope to benefit from.
At the time, Mr. Shimada thought I had something he could steal, which is why he invited me.
As for me, I said I wanted to join because I thought I had something to offer, even if what I had to offer wasn't a lot.
And that's why that day still sticks out in my mind.
There's still something that I want to ask him.
Until I get an answer, all I can do is try to hold on.
Right.
The next day, Mr. Shimada went to Tokushima.
The curtain was about to be lifted on the third match of the Shishio Tournament.
Well, look who it is. You just barely made it, Ray.
Oh, hey.
I hear that everyone's going to Mouse Land the day after tomorrow for the farewell party.
What do you think about that? But, as usual, I wasn't invited.
I don't know why you tell me stuff like that when I've mentioned not to over and over all year long.
I kind of feel like this is getting pretty close to bullying.
Nothing here has changed at all.
I squeaked by with my attendants, and I didn't join a club.
My rank hasn't changed at all either.
I haven't accomplished anything.
You know, the only reason I was able to make it to the next grade was because of you, sir.
Thanks a lot for everything.
Knock it off.
Haven't accomplished anything.
That's nonsense.
You've been coming to school all this time while working.
You make your own meals.
You take out the trash and do your own laundry.
You are a fighter.
You make your own money.
And you pay your own rent.
I remember when I was your age.
I thought, I bet I'm going to be a big shot when I grow up.
I aimlessly held on to that dream.
While playing games.
Reading manga.
Hanging out with friends.
Watching TV.
I never had to worry about paying rent or saving money.
And I certainly never had to clean up or make any of my meals.
So don't tell me you haven't accomplished anything.
You did the best you could.
And I watched you do it.
I wish he would stop.
He's always like this.
Insensitive and outspoken.
I just wish he would stop.
When he starts getting like this.
I really can't handle it.
Hey.
Look, it's cold out.
How about we go grab some food?
My treat.
To celebrate you passing.
It's okay.
Thanks, though.
Then how about going to Mouse Land?
The two of us!
Come on!
What do you say?
Let's go right now!
No, that's okay.
Some food sounds good.
And so, my short spring vacation finally began.
The Shishio Tournament.
Match three.
Day two.
Mr. Shimada is in a tight spot.
The only thing he can do now is hold on.
Plus, he's been spending more time deciding his moves.
One more loss and the next one is do or die.
All straight losses.
I can't let that happen.
Mr. Shimada.
Please.
Coming!
Who could that be?
Hina.
And Momo.
Um, hi.
Ray.
The reason we're here is to get our boxes.
Scratch.
Restless.
Okay.
Just give me a second and I'll get you both something to drink.
What do I have that I can serve them?
Tea is fine for adults.
But what do I give a middle schooler and a kindergartner?
Do you have any tea to go with this Inari Sushi?
Do you have any chocolate?
I feel like munching on something that's sweet.
Why don't you have any soda?
Well, thank you for the sushi.
It was delicious.
You finished it?
You really ate all of it?
Yeah.
I ate it all.
Actually, she ate most of it.
I only had two pieces.
So, yeah.
I like the one with wasabi the best.
Well, that's good.
I'm glad to hear it.
Akari and I made the Inari Sushi together.
It turned out really well for girls' festivals, so we made some for you, too.
Well, Grandpa likes the wasabi ones a lot, so we made you some extras.
Now!
Who was that?
That woman you were with!
Noah!
What woman?
The woman I saw!
How do I put this?
I, um...
I was wondering if you were okay, because I was worried.
It looked like you were having an argument with her.
It's just that...
It looked to me like you were on the receiving end of it.
And I was wondering if you were okay with it.
Is...
Is she a witch?
Huh.
If I really was a witch...
I wouldn't be in such pathetic shape.
No, she's not.
She's not a witch.
It's not like that at all.
You see...
She's my...
older sister.
Older sister?
Yeah, that's right.
She's my stepsister.
So sometimes we fight.
But it's okay.
We're still family.
It's the same at your house, too, isn't it?
Yeah, it's the same.
My sister, Akari, and Hina get into fights all the time.
And Hina ends up crying a lot, too.
That's it, Mom!
Stop it, Mama!
Mama knows they're still family.
Exactly.
We're home!
The mystery's solved!
Guess what?
You won't believe it!
That woman was raised older sister!
I feel so much better now!
I was worried over nothing!
It was just a brother and sister argument!
Who would have thought?
Very interesting.
But Hina, I think that's probably worse.
I'm so worried.
It's the best of her.
It's Squirrely Sensei time!
Let's watch!
Yeah!
Let's watch Squirrely Sensei!
I'm so hungry!
Forget about that Squirrely and give me some food!
I'm hungry!
In fact, I'm so hungry I could eat that darn Squirrely!
They lived in the same house for nearly ten years.
And yet, when we saw them together, they didn't seem like brother and sister at all.
I see, Rei.
So, that's why you left home, isn't it?
The third match of the Shishio Tournament.
After 113 moves, Kai Shimada, eighth dan, conceded.
And at five o'clock, I heard a familiar tune being played throughout town.
I realized, for the very first time, that the song that was playing was called, Hometown.
So tell me what Grandmaster Soya's really like in person.
He really does piss me off, though.
Always looking so young and adorable with a full head of hair.
Well then, if you don't mind, I guess I should be heading home now.
One, two, don't miss the next, March Comes In Like A Lion!
I wonder what Squirrely Sensei likes to eat.
GAM!
You know what I'm making a sparklingined fundraiser?
What did you do with me?
Going on?
Al prais!
No!